<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<Section title="Mipmaps"
         id="b8d20538-e4ac-4674-aa43-d5ab93c07149"
         xmlns="urn:com.io7m.structural:8:0"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">

  <Paragraph>
    A texture consists of a sequence of <Term type="term">mipmaps</Term>. A sequence of
    mipmaps is a sequence of progressively scaled-down copies of a <Term type="term">base image</Term>.
    Each mipmap <Term type="term">level</Term> is numbered with the base image being at level
    <Term type="constant">0</Term> and the number of each subsequent level is the successor of the
    number of the previous level. The mipmap image at each level is half the width and height
    of the previous level.
  </Paragraph>

  <Paragraph>
    A mipmap stores an <Term type="term">offset</Term> indicating the start of the actual image data for the mipmap
    relative to the first octet of the first mipmap declaration. A mipmap also stores the
    <Link target="8f83a47a-986e-4dba-bfd7-720641cee3a9">compressed size</Link> and uncompressed size of the
    image data, along with a
    <LinkExternal target="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cyclic_redundancy_check">CRC32</LinkExternal> checksum
    of the <Term type="term">uncompressed</Term> data. A CRC32 value of <Term type="constant">0</Term> indicates
    that no checksum is available. For uncompressed data, the compressed and uncompressed sizes must equal the
    size of the uncompressed data.
  </Paragraph>

  <Paragraph>
    Mipmap sequences are stored such that the data for the mipmap with the highest level is encountered
    <Term type="term">first</Term>, whilst the data for the mipmap with level <Term type="constant">0</Term>
    is encountered <Term type="term">last</Term>. This facilitates a common implementation pattern where
    textures are progressively streamed onto the GPU starting with the highest mipmap levels first. The
    inductive proposition <Term type="expression">mipMapOffsetsSorted</Term> declares that, for a given mipmap
    <Term type="expression">m</Term>, the offset of <Term type="expression">m</Term> plus the compressed size of
    <Term type="expression">m</Term> aligned to the required
    <Link target="e92704bb-ce55-4d97-8a9a-7d3b495a5d35">texel block alignment</Link>,
    must be less than the offset of the next mipmap in the sequence.
  </Paragraph>

  <FormalItem title="MipMap">
    <Verbatim><xi:include href="70.txt" parse="text" /></Verbatim>
  </FormalItem>
  <FormalItem title="MipMap Sequence Sorting">
    <Verbatim><xi:include href="71.txt" parse="text" /></Verbatim>
  </FormalItem>
  <FormalItem title="MipMap Offsets Sorting">
    <Verbatim><xi:include href="102.txt" parse="text" /></Verbatim>
  </FormalItem>
  <FormalItem title="MipMap Sequence">
    <Verbatim><xi:include href="72.txt" parse="text" /></Verbatim>
  </FormalItem>

  <Paragraph>
    Given a base image of size <Term type="expression">(sizeX, sizeY)</Term>, the size of the mipmap
    at level <Term type="expression">n</Term> is given by <Term type="expression">(sizeX / 2ⁿ, sizeY / 2ⁿ)</Term>.
    Mipmap images are required to be of a size <Term type="expression">&gt;= 2</Term> on the X and Y axes. Note
    that this restriction does <Term type="emphasis">not</Term> apply to the base image; a base image with a size
    of 1 on any axis simply cannot have anything but a level 0 mipmap.
  </Paragraph>

  <FormalItem title="MipMap Size">
    <Verbatim><xi:include href="75.txt" parse="text" /></Verbatim>
  </FormalItem>
  <FormalItem title="MipMap Size Calculation">
    <Verbatim><xi:include href="74.txt" parse="text" /></Verbatim>
  </FormalItem>

  <Paragraph id="8522affa-6919-4bc2-9aaa-fbfde3e73570">
    The total size required to hold the image data for all mipmaps is effectively equal to the offset of the
    largest mipmap, plus the compressed size of the mipmap, rounded up to the required alignment of the image data.
  </Paragraph>

  <FormalItem title="MipMap Data Size (Aux)">
    <Verbatim><xi:include href="103.txt" parse="text" /></Verbatim>
  </FormalItem>
  <FormalItem title="MipMap Data Size">
    <Verbatim><xi:include href="104.txt" parse="text" /></Verbatim>
  </FormalItem>

</Section>
